Guide to the Memorial Quadrangle, Yale University, Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Memorial Quadrangle, Yale University, photographs
1917-1977
RU 695
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7.25
The materials consist of photographs and pictures of Memorial Quadrangle at Yale, including interiors, exteriors, and a catalogue of decoration and ornament. Photographs of plans and architect's models are also included.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-B (YRG 46-B), Records and materials documenting individual Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by topic.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs and pictures of Memorial Quadrangle at Yale, including interiors, exteriors, and a catalogue of decoration and ornament. Photographs of plans and architect's models are also included.
College buildings -- Design and construction; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings
- Photographs, Series I
  - Articles and general information (xerox) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles and general information (printed) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General views (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Elm Street side (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - York Street side (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Library Street side
    - pre-1933 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
    - post-1933 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - High Street side (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Harkness Tower
    General note
    See also: Oversize, box 7, folders 1-4
    - Construction, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Drawings, etchings, miscellaneous views (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - From Branford Court (Box 1, Folder 12 - 13)
    - From Library Street (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - From Old Campus, pre-1926 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - From Old Campus, night, 1940s-1950s (Box 2, Folder 16 - 17)
    - From Old Campus (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - From High Street, to North (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - From High Street, to South (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Chimes-original ten bells prior to installation, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Chimes-original ten bells, installed (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Carillon, installation, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Wrexham Tower, Circa 1920 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Wrexham Tower (Box 2, Folder 25 - 26)
  - "The Tourelle," from Branford Court (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Moats (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Interior, miscellaneous dormitory rooms, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Interior, bathroom, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Ornament
    - Cornerstone, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Saybrook millstone, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Branford millstone
      - transporting the stone, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - transporting the stone, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - in place, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Killingworth millstone (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Windows (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Entryway inscriptions (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Stone carving (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Catalog of models
      - index (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - plates 1-24 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - plates 25-48 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - plates 49-72 (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - index (copy 2) (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - plates 1-24 (copy 2) (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - plates 25-48 (copy 2) (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - plates 49-72 (copy 2) (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Branford College
    See also: Oversize, box 7
    - Branford Court
      - general, pre-1933 (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - general, post-1933 (Box 4, Folder 49 - 50)
      - south side (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - north side, pre-1933 (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - north side, post-1933 (Box 5, Folder 53)
      - west side, pre-1933 (Box 5, Folder 54)
      - west side, post-1933 (Box 5, Folder 55)
      - east side (Box 5, Folder 56)
      - entryways (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Dana Entry, Calliope Court (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Johnson Entryway (Master's House entryway) (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Brothers-in-Unity Court (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Calliope Court (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Linonia Court (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Davenport Gateway (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Drummer Gateway (Box 5, Folder 64)
      General
      See also: box 6, folder 84 See also: box 6, folder 87
    - Eliot Gateway (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Fitch Gateway (Box 5, Folder 66)
      See also: box 6, folder 88
    - Livingston Gateway (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Mather Gateway (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Memorial Gateway
      - court side before wrought iron gate, Circa 1921 (Box 5, Folder 69)
      - court side with wrought iron gate, post-1922 (Box 5, Folder 70)
      - High Street side, before wrought iron gate, Circa 1921 (Box 5, Folder 71)
      - High Street side, with wrought iron gate, post-1922 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Pierpont Gateway (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Dwight-Edwards passageway (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Interior: Memorial Room (Chapel) (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Interior: Dining Hall (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Interiors: Common Rooms (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Saybrook College
    See also: Oversize, box 7, folder 6
    - Killingworth Court
      - prior to 1933 remodeling (Box 6, Folder 78)
      - following 1933 (Box 6, Folder 79)
      - entryways (Box 6, Folder 80)
    - Saybrook Court
      - prior to 1933 remodeling (Box 6, Folder 81)
      - following 1933 (Box 6, Folder 82)
      - entryways (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - Wrexham Court (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - Wrexham Court, entryways (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - Berkeley Gateway (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - Drummer Gateway (Box 6, Folder 87)
      See also: box 5, folder 64 See also: box 6, folders 84-85
    - Fitch Gateway (Box 6, Folder 88)
      See also: box 5, folder 66
    - Saltonstall Gateway (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - Master's House (Box 6, Folder 90)
    - Founder's Day, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 91)
    - Interior, Library (Box 6, Folder 92)
    - Interior, Common Rooms (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - Interior, Room 1002 (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - Plans (photographs of)
    - Architect's models, Circa 1920 (Box 6, Folder 95)
    - Elevations, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 96)
    - Assignment plan, Circa 1933 (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - Planting plan, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 98)
  - OVERSIZE
    - Preliminary sketches by James Gamble Rogers (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Harkness Tower
      - Exterior (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - with Pierson Statue (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Interior (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - View from Hotel Taft, Circa 1922-1924 (pre-1925) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - View from Branford courtyard, Circa 1921 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Branford College (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Saybrook College (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Wrexham Tower, Circa 1970 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - SLIDES and TRANSPARENCIES
  - Slides (Box CS1, Folder 19)
  - Slides (cont'd) (Box CS1, Folder 20)
  - Slides (cont'd) (Box CS2, Folder 21)
  - Transparencies
    - Branford College (Box CS8, Folder 149)
    - Branford College (cont'd) (Box CS8, Folder 150)
    - Branford Court (Box CS8, Folder 151)
    - Branford, Saybrook, Wrexham Towers (Box CS8, Folder 152)
    - Branford, Saybrook, Wrexham Towers (cont'd) (Box CS8, Folder 153)
    - Harkness Tower (Box CS8, Folder 154)
    - Harkness Tower (cont'd) (Box CS8, Folder 155)
    - Harkness Tower (cont'd) (Box CS8, Folder 156)
    - Harkness Tower (Box CS9, Folder 157)
    - Saybrook College, exterior (Box CS9, Folder 158)
    - Saybrook College, exterior (cont'd) (Box CS9, Folder 159)
    - Saybrook College, exterior (cont'd) (Box CS9, Folder 160)
    - Saybrook College, Wrexham Tower (Box CS9, Folder 161)
    - Saybrook College, courtyard (Box CS9, Folder 162)
    - Saybrook College, Killingworth Court (Box CS9, Folder 163)
- Photograph album of Memorial Quadrangle, circa 1925; Accession 2000-A-065
  - Album (Box 1)